[
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": " Foster the economic welfare of the EU member states by requiring an application of IFRS for all companies in the EU.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.329Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "udymja6okx2e7vf",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Bring transparency by enhancing the international comparability and quality of financial information, enabling investors to make informed economic decisions.",
      "Contribute to economic efficiency by helping investors to identify opportunities and risks across the world, thus improving capital allocation.",
      "Bring accountability by reducing the information gap between the providers of capital and the people to whom they have entrusted their money."
    ],
    "question": "What is not an explicit mission of the IASB?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.329Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... Mandatory contributions of preparers.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.330Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "2lijzaay1sy7gi2",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... accounting firms.",
      "... selling books with standards.",
      "... German companies."
    ],
    "question": "The funding of the IASB does not come from ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.330Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... come from different countries.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.330Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "ou3w0m1xlhuiupw",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... are always more than 16.",
      "... vote on the application of IFRS in different countries.",
      "... have meetings every week in a year."
    ],
    "question": "The members of the IASB...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.330Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... an EFRAG opinion on the IFRS standard",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.331Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "r8cv28fven5q9em",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... final IFRS standard",
      "... an exposure draft",
      "... a discussion paper"
    ],
    "question": "The due process does not involve a ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.331Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... approval process of the EU for newly issued IFRSs.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.331Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "s2lhxf7bd8zfedx",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... monitoring of the implementation of existing IFRSs.",
      "... first step of the due process of the IASB.",
      "... enacting of the IAS Regulation."
    ],
    "question": "Endorsement is the ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.331Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... Bilanzrechtsreformgesetz.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.332Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "a2oj2k5foxvtd13",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... Deutsche Prüfstelle für Rechnungslegung.",
      "... Bundesanstalt für Finanzdienstleistungsaufsicht.",
      "... Capital Raising Act."
    ],
    "question": "The IAS Regulation was implemented in Germany by the ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.332Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Accounting Regulatory Committee",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.332Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "703zxuc2qo2szhu",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Accounting Regulation Cooperation",
      "Accounting Rules Concert",
      "Accounting Revision Committee"
    ],
    "question": "What does ARC mean (in the context of international accounting)?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.332Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... is part of total comprehensive income",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.333Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "izf2u3vm2plv827",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... arises from transaction with shareholders",
      "... is part of profit or loss for the period",
      "... is recognized in the cash flow statement"
    ],
    "question": "Other comprehensive income ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.333Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Enforcement",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.334Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "7rmxl1g6m3kb1wr",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Endorsement",
      "Issuing new IFRSs",
      "Issuing new IFRS interpretations"
    ],
    "question": "What is the primary focus of ESMA?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.334Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "The IASC issued IASs.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.335Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "ymdyolg2iwcqmad",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "The IASC issued endorsement recommendations.",
      "The IASB issues IASs.",
      "The IASC issued IFRSs."
    ],
    "question": "Which statement is correct?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.335Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Announcement of the error",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.336Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "pyqq5c5xm3mdjup",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Jail sentences",
      "Delisting of shares",
      "No longer allowed to apply IFRS"
    ],
    "question": "What is the most important sanction in the German enforcement system?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.336Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Balance Sheet",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.337Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "4t1bdwu6aty947h",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Income Statement",
      "Cash Flow Statement",
      "Statement of Changes in Equity"
    ],
    "question": "What is another name of the Statement of Financial Position?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.337Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... whether the standard is enforced.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.338Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "8iquf3btrav7tu8",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... whether the standard is contrary to the ‘true and fair view’ (TFV) principle.",
      "... whether the standard is conducive to the European public good.",
      "... whether the standard meets the criteria of understandability, relevance and reliability."
    ],
    "question": "Not a criterion for the endorsement of IFRSs is ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.338Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... all publicly traded companies to apply IFRS in their consolidated financial statements.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.339Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "1x6z283u7w9hnjq",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... all publicly traded companies to apply IFRS in their individual financial statements.",
      "... all non-publicly traded companies to apply IFRS in their consolidated financial statements.",
      "... all non-publicly traded companies to apply national GAAP in their financial statements."
    ],
    "question": "The IAS Regulation since 2005 requires...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.339Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Time from buying raw materials until selling finished goods.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.340Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "t9s3fkh7ir44zlt",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Time from hiring a manager until he/she leaves the firm.",
      "Time from recognizing an item in the balance sheet until its derecognition.",
      "Time from buying inventories until using them in the production process."
    ],
    "question": "What is the operating cycle of a manufacturing company?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.340Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Specific standard on the event/transaction",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.341Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "d7cbsxzd168u90c",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Accounting literature",
      "Industry practices",
      "Conceptual framework"
    ],
    "question": "What is the most important basis to applied to an event/transaction according to the IFRS hierarchy?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.341Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Practical tool to assist users to understand and interpret IFRSs.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.342Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "epk31mwg5sy8a0n",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Basic principles for the IASB for the endorsement of the IFRSs.",
      "Practical tool to assist the IASB to supervise the IFRS Foundation.",
      "Practical tool to assist the IASB to coordinate enforcement bodies."
    ],
    "question": "What is the Conceptual Framework of the IASB?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.342Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Lenders",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.343Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "rygv5vnllgnklct",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Taxation Authorities",
      "Academics",
      "Enforcement agencies"
    ],
    "question": "According to the Conceptual Framework one of the primary users of financial statements are ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.343Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Statement of Future Cash Flows",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.344Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "mwzeaw7m2xecs2m",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Statement of Performance",
      "Statement of Changes in Equity",
      "Notes"
    ],
    "question": "What is not a mandatory component of financial statements under IFRS?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.344Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... appoints the IASB members.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.345Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "ssud18rdbht0vgg",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... issues IFRS standards.",
      "... appoints the IASB monitoring board members.",
      "... is responsible for the endorsement of IFRS standards."
    ],
    "question": "The IFRS Foundation ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.345Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Item's cost or value can be measured with reliability.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.346Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "u8r7lmqdbymoh5v",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "A resource controlled by the enterprise.",
      "Future economic benefits are expected to flow to the enterprise.",
      "Enterprise received the item as a result of past events."
    ],
    "question": "What is not a requirement for an asset?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.346Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Shares of other companies",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.347Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "z74fgaf8311umyi",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Bitcoins",
      "Money in the till"
    ],
    "question": "What is not presented under the item “cash and cash equivalents”?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.347Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Current and non-current items",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.348Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "10cto5sbmqb46tj",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Long-term and non-long-term items",
      "Fixed and non-fixed items",
      "Tangible and non-tangible items"
    ],
    "question": "How is the Statement of Financial Position basically structured?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.348Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "dr2w23v6mk00pw9",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... other comprehensive income and profit or loss.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.348Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "x61u827mhxqmvc9",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... changes in equity from transaction with shareholders and profit or loss.",
      "... other profit or loss and net income.",
      "... profit or loss and other changes in equity."
    ],
    "question": "Total Comprehensive Income consists of ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.348Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": " ... carrying amount of an asset exceeds its recoverable amount.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.349Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "x190id3wkrnatwf",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... carrying amount of an asset is lower than its recoverable amount.",
      "... book value of an asset is lower than its original cost.",
      "... book value of an asset exceeds its original cost."
    ],
    "question": "An impairment loss is calculated as the amount by which​ the...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.349Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... the cost of an asset less its residual value.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.350Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "l2cp13tpu2ohrug",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... the cost of an asset plus its residual value.",
      "... the process of allocating an expense to an asset.",
      "... the useful life of an asset."
    ],
    "question": "The depreciable amount is...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.350Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... cost less (minus) accumulated depreciation and any impairment losses",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.350Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "4c9snwrsdox5kb3",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... always at initial cost.",
      "... cost less (minus) accumulated depreciation and impairment losses are disclosed in the notes.",
      "... always at fair value less cost to sell."
    ],
    "question": "Using the cost model, PPE is measured subsequent to recognition:",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.350Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "On a regular basis when fair values change, or are expected to change",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.351Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "xct8uq4z2gzh0n1",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Always annually",
      "Always every 3-5 years",
      "Never"
    ],
    "question": "In the revaluation model, revaluations are required:",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.351Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... all components are recognized and depreciated separately.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.351Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "rldi6d31mrrxijp",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... all components are recognized and depreciated aggregately.",
      "... all components always have the same useful life.",
      "... all components always have the same cost."
    ],
    "question": "In the component approach, when components have different useful lifes and have significant cost compared to the total cost of the PPE asset...\r\n",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.351Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "35% * (cost of the asset - accumulated depreciation)",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.352Z",
    "footer": "The asterisk (*) in the question is the multiplication operator.",
    "id": "okdaal45c1rpzcb",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "35% * cost of the asset",
      "35% * accumulated depreciation",
      "35% * (cost of the asset + accumulated depreciation)"
    ],
    "question": "For a PPE asset, the depreciation charge for the year, calculated using the diminishing balance basis at the rate of 35%, in case there is no impairment loss, would be arrived at as follows:",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.352Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Straight-line method",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.353Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "4a2g3n3awezgiah",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Diminishing balance method",
      "It does not matter which depreciation method is used.",
      "There is no need for depreciation in t1."
    ],
    "question": "A firm purchases new machines for 11.000€ in t0 and aims at showing a net income as high as possible in t1. The useful life is 5 years and the residual value is 1.000€. Which of the following depreciation models should the firm choose with respect to the new machines?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.353Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Stock market crash",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.354Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "h94hysnsw2h9mop",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Loss of key personnel",
      "Major reorganizations",
      "Physical damage"
    ],
    "question": "Which is not an internal indicator for an impairment:",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.354Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Each reporting period",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.355Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "pskhpkdxbuy4dkv",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Each month",
      "Every 2-3 years",
      "Never"
    ],
    "question": "When do firms shall assess whether there is an indicator that an asset may be impaired?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.355Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... impaired.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.355Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "q8uk8gp1vd8qp38",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... in a revaluation deficit.",
      "... flawed.",
      "... in negative equity."
    ],
    "question": "When the recoverable amount of an asset is less than its carrying value in the Statement of Financial Position, the asset is...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.355Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "The higher of fair value less costs to sell and value in use.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.356Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "t0le62ot27s0ptb",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "The lower of its cost and net realizable value.",
      "The lower of net present value and cost.",
      "The higher of net present value and cost."
    ],
    "question": "Under IAS 36, what is the recoverable amount of an asset?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.356Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "When the fair value can be reliably measured.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.358Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "7og5mpmnvz556dv",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "When the PPE includes unrecorded intangible assets.",
      "When the fair value of the PPE exceeds the book value by 10%.",
      "When the value of the PPE has been impaired."
    ],
    "question": "Under IAS 16, what is a necessary condition to use the revaluation model to measure property, plant, and equipment (PPE)?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.358Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "gftsg6bdm8im7eq",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Cost model and revaluation model",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.360Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "sycp1z635epbnfg",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Cost model and present value model",
      "Fair value model and revaluation model",
      "Fair value model and cost model"
    ],
    "question": "Under IAS 16, which of the following accounting treatments are allowed subsequently to initial recognition?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.360Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... future economic benefits can be measured reliably.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.363Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "g08hyn5kvsipe0l",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... identifiability.",
      "... non-monetary asset.",
      "... no physical substance."
    ],
    "question": "The definition of intangible assets according to IAS 38 does not require ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.363Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... brands.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.365Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "qc1e7ayakhj1ihk",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... money in bank accounts.",
      "... buildings used for rental income.",
      "... machines which are no longer used in the production."
    ],
    "question": "An example for intangible assets are ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.365Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Acquired brands are always recognized because it is assumed that they generate future economic benefits and that their cost can be measured reliably.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.366Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "1bbo93h35fqh40d",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Self-generated brands that will be sold in future are recognised because they will generate future econmic benefits.",
      "Acquired brands are only recognised if they are generated in the development phase and fulfill 6 criteria.",
      "Self-generated brands are only recognised if they are generated in the development phase and fulfill 6 criteria."
    ],
    "question": "What is correct?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.366Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "A firm uses a prototype which was developed by TUM to develop new batteries for electric vehicles.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.367Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "ukqkv0h2c2k4711",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "A firm searches for a new process to produce batteries for electric vehicles.",
      "A firm buys a license for a new process to produce batteries for their electric vehicles.",
      "A firm searches for applications of new research findings of TUM to develop a new process to produce batteries for their electric vehicles."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following are development costs?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.367Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... all costs are expensed.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.370Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "ryepwatin8nf4aa",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... all costs are capitalised.",
      "... all costs are capitalised if 6 requirements are fulfilled.",
      "... all costs are expensed if 6 requirements are fulfilled."
    ],
    "question": "If an entity cannot distinguish research phase and development phase ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.370Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "ability to monitor the development process.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.373Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "fxwl0y9vkvnsevr",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "technical feasibility of completing the intangible asset for use/sale.",
      "ability to measure reliably the expenditures.",
      "intention to complete the intangible asset."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following does not have to be fulfilled in order to recognize development costs?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.373Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Brands.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.375Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "bmbi5a84xeis8cb",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Computer software.",
      "Patented technology.",
      "Motion pictures."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following intangible assets cannot be recognized if it is self- generated?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.375Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... the cost model or in the case of an active market the revaluation model.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.376Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "oo90zhr65yemjkc",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... the cost model only.",
      "... the fair value model only.",
      "... the revaluation model only."
    ],
    "question": "Intangible assets are measured at the balance sheet date using ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.376Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... intangible assets with an indefinite useful life.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.377Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "22ihh4g0wxpw6r2",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... inventories.",
      "... intangible assets for which an active market exists.",
      "... intangible assets resulting from development costs."
    ],
    "question": "The impairment only approach is used for ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.377Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Inventories.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.378Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "vgd43rsxkw8hh27",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Intangible assets with definite useful life.",
      "Property, plant and equipment.",
      "Intangible assets with indefinite useful life."
    ],
    "question": "For which assets is the impairment test never relevant?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.378Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Trademarks.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.379Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "eyutotltagbsr1u",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Patents.",
      "Computer software.",
      "Machines."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following assets can have a indefinite useful life?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.379Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Production quotas.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.380Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "94aikouhrtcoyfk",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Patents.",
      "Motion picture.",
      "Trademarks."
    ],
    "question": "For which of the following assets can an active market exist?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.380Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Capital Asset Pricing Model.",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.436Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "pizt1pvb303o1v0",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Cost Model.",
      "Revaluation Model.",
      "All listed models are permitted."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following measurement models is not permitted for the subsequent measurement of intangible assets under IAS 38",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.436Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Its expected useful life",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.438Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "zorzf2sfcixtkoy",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "A period at the discretion of management",
      "Five years",
      "No foreseeable limit"
    ],
    "question": "An intangible asset with a finite useful life should be amortised over:",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.438Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "c6renzs6o1jr9ps",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Profit or Loss",
    "created": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.439Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "l9z39bmxzy22w07",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Equity",
      "Statement of Financial Position",
      "Statement of Cash Flows"
    ],
    "question": "Where is the amortisation of an intangible asset recognised?",
    "updated": "2026-02-18 23:38:51.439Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "eg8rimxfcn5hxx5",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Last in, First out (‘LIFO’)",
    "created": "2026-02-19 10:53:36.920Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "75sjg2qq5nr4jkj",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "First in, First out (‘FIFO’)",
      "Weighted Average"
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following cost formulas is not permitted under IAS 2?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 10:55:24.685Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "eg8rimxfcn5hxx5",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Lower of cost and net realisable value",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:17:02.749Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "v0einwf89gdlz32",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Lower of cost and carrying value",
      "Lower of fair value and net realisable value",
      "Cost of production"
    ],
    "question": "Inventories are measured at:",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:17:02.749Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "eg8rimxfcn5hxx5",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Tangible assets lying in the store, which are intended for sale",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:19:01.940Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "qtwlzxjbwca8e5v",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Machinery used in the production process which is for sale",
      "Productions Plants",
      "Intangible assets used in the production process, but not intended for sale"
    ],
    "question": "Inventories include:",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:19:01.940Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "eg8rimxfcn5hxx5",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... Net realisable value",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:19:39.700Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "0ijwzi76c2jj0xi",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... Fair value",
      "... Market value",
      "... Recoverable amount"
    ],
    "question": "Inventory should be measured at the lower of cost and...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:19:39.700Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "eg8rimxfcn5hxx5",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... recognised as an expense in the period in which the write-down occurs",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:20:48.452Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "t2r4vvsqg3fzafc",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... recognized in the other comprehensive income",
      "... recognized as a current liability in the balance sheet",
      "... recognised as an expense in the subsequent period in which such write-down is warranted"
    ],
    "question": "Any amount of write-down of inventories to net realisable value should be...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:20:48.452Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "eg8rimxfcn5hxx5",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "The cost of Inventory is $3.700 and the cost of sales is $1.200",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:21:58.092Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "xq2qprlp1vqjsym",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "The cost of Inventory is $3.7000 and the cost of sales is $1.000",
      "The cost of Inventory is $3.900 and the cost of sales is $1.400",
      "The cost of Inventory is $3.700 and the cost of sales is $4.900"
    ],
    "question": "Zippy Machines is in the business of procuring raw materials and sells them to international markets. During the year, the Company bought four tons of raw materials costing 1.200€, 1.400€, 1.300€ and 1.000€ respectively.\r\nDuring the year it sold only one tone for 1.400€ and follows the FIFO method of valuation. Which of the following statements is TRUE?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:21:58.092Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "eg8rimxfcn5hxx5",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Net realisable value",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:23:07.319Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "nvvfpl2o07ivian",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Recoverable Amount",
      "Market value",
      "Fair value"
    ],
    "question": "The estimated selling price in the ordinary course of business, less any completion costs and costs of sale is called...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:23:07.319Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "​338.800€",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:26:35.258Z",
    "footer": "To-Do: add auto equation generator: 284.400+842.800-(985.500/1,25)",
    "id": "bt1ah1n5n0xx52j",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "230.000€",
      "388.075€",
      "229.984€"
    ],
    "question": "A retail trader fixes his sale price by adding​ 25% to the cost of every item purchased. You are informed that opening inventory was 284.400€, purchases were 842.800€ (equal purchase prices for all items) and sales were ​985.500€. Closing inventory should be:",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:30:10.543Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "37.500€",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:29:52.046Z",
    "footer": "To-Do: add auto equation generator: ((10.000*3+5.000*4+5.000*5)/20.000)*10.000, add table",
    "id": "gy8rg1cm9d6gxln",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "30.000€",
      "56.000€",
      "40.000€"
    ],
    "question": "Handy Ltd values its closing inventory using the weighted average method. What is the amount for the cost of goods sold?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:29:52.046Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "eg8rimxfcn5hxx5",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... average cost",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:31:15.569Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "y5n1743es6mraa1",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... FIFO",
      "... LIFO",
      "... none of these"
    ],
    "question": "In a period of rising prices, the inventory method which is allowed under IFRS and tends to give the highest reported cost of goods sold is:",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:31:15.569Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "4a9a9l5hitzl4w7",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "A liability with uncertain amount or timing.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:33:24.923Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "z1nl2gfuy5o22mo",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "A contingent liability with uncertain future cash flows.",
      "A economic benefit to a third party due to a future event.",
      "An entry in other comprehensive income."
    ],
    "question": "What is a provision?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:33:24.923Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "4a9a9l5hitzl4w7",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... that it is identifiable.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:34:20.395Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "njs32l6hza7x2kl",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... that the amount can be measured reliably.",
      "... that the outflow of economic benefits is probable.",
      "... that it results from a past event."
    ],
    "question": "The recognition of a provision does not require ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:34:20.395Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "4a9a9l5hitzl4w7",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "A management decisions to repair a machine.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:35:58.594Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "vr2b89mo5lsxeb9",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "A sale contract for products with warranties.",
      "A pattern of past practice of paying bonuses to employees.",
      "A court order to decontaminate land."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following is not a present obligation from which a provision can result ?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:36:05.561Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "4a9a9l5hitzl4w7",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Possible but not probable and not remote.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:37:03.109Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "xpq5r1wn77hyw62",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Probable but not remote and not possible.",
      "Remote but not possible and not probable.",
      "None of the listed."
    ],
    "question": "What are the probability requirements for the outflow of future economic benefits for a contingent liability?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:37:03.109Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "4a9a9l5hitzl4w7",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... best estimate.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:37:32.602Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "jc3s48brlgtxmw4",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... cost.",
      "... probability weighted fair value.",
      "... net realisable value."
    ],
    "question": "Provisions are measured at ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:37:32.602Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "4a9a9l5hitzl4w7",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... the estimated cash ouflow with the highest likelihood.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:38:13.771Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "ncn2t8dyu7bmu9k",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... the most likely cash inflow.",
      "... the probability-weighted expected value.",
      "... the most likely fair value."
    ],
    "question": "If the risks specific to the liability and the time value\r\nof money are ignored a provision for a lawsuit is measured at ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:38:13.771Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "15,000€.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:39:21.355Z",
    "footer": "To-Do: add auto equation generator",
    "id": "7u62lqb1gc2gej5",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "5,000€.",
      "10,000€.",
      "20,000€."
    ],
    "question": "An entity sells 2,000 units of a product with warranties under which the entity will repair any manufacturing defects that become apparent within the first six months after purchase. If a minor defect is detected in a product, estimated repair costs of 50€ will result. If a major defect is detected in a product, estimated repair costs of 100€ will result. The entity’s experience together with its future expectations indicate that 90 per cent of the goods sold have no defects, 5 per cent of the goods sold have minor defects and 5 per cent of the goods sold have major defects. What is the value of the provision to be recognized?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:39:21.355Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "4a9a9l5hitzl4w7",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "DR provision 1 Mio. CR income 1 Mio.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:40:01.496Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "lqixwe0sigrqw0o",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "DR income 1 Mio. CR provision 1 Mio.",
      "DR provision 1 Mio. CR cash 1 Mio.",
      "DR provision 1 Mio. CR expenses 1 Mio."
    ],
    "question": "An entity wins a lawsuit in 2016 for which a provision of 1 Mio. € was recognized in 2015 for the case of a loss. What are the necessary booking entries?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:40:01.496Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "A contract that gives rise to a financial liability or equity instrument of one entity and a financial asset of another entity.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:41:13.178Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "d6qcnz2w5rb0o62",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "A firm policy that gives rise to a financial asset of one entity and a financial liability or equity instrument of another entity.",
      "A contract that results in a financial asset of one entity and a liability instrument of another entity.",
      "A contract that gives rise to equity instruments of two entities."
    ],
    "question": "What is a financial instrument?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:41:13.178Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Accounts payables.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:42:11.964Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "y4iw41emjrcg853",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Cash.",
      "A forward with a positive value.",
      "An option to sell shares of an entity."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following is not a financial asset?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:42:11.964Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Buying an option for selling shares of an entity for 50 Euros and current market value of the shares is 60 Euros.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:43:09.975Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "bdyxgvaz48yi4dz",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Issuing a 10-year industry bond",
      "Being granted a loan of 1 Mio. Euros by Deutsche Bank.",
      "A forward for buying crude oil in 1 year for 50 Euros per barrel and the current market value of 1 barrel of crude oil is 40 Euros."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following does not give rise to a financial liability?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:43:09.975Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... amortised cost.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:43:51.899Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "jhc89pe88846ayg",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... fair value through other comprehensive income.",
      "... fair value through profit and loss.",
      "... net realisable value."
    ],
    "question": "A debt instrument for which the business model is hold the financial instrument and collect the contractual cash flows and for which the SSPI criterion is fulfilled is measured at ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:43:51.899Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... fair value through profit and loss.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:44:25.691Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "usqdb4car8wgjwh",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... amortised cost.",
      "... fair value through other comprehensive income.",
      "... net realisable value."
    ],
    "question": "Forward contracts are measured at ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:44:25.691Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "... only at fair value through profit and loss.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:45:23.650Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "by4jwdzwdl2ly7i",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... only at amortised cost.",
      "... only at fair value through other comprehensive income.",
      "... fair value through profit and loss or fair value through other comprehensive income."
    ],
    "question": "Shares which are held for trading are measured ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:45:23.650Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": " ... quoted market prices.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:46:04.672Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "nljqr7ffzz5bd33",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... discounted future cashflows.",
      "... results of an valuation model.",
      "... best estimates."
    ],
    "question": "The best measure for the fair value of financial instruments (level 1) are...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:46:04.672Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "DR expenses 2 Mio., CR financial liability 2 Mio.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:46:55.811Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "f9ebgp4y8hr9f9z",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "DR expenses 2 Mio., CR financial asset 2 Mio.",
      "DR other comprehensive income, 2 Mio., CR financial liability 2 Mio.",
      "DR other comprehensive income 2 Mio. CR financial asset 2 Mio."
    ],
    "question": "A forward is measured at the balance sheet date. The value was – 2 Mio. at the last balance sheet date and now is – 4 Mio. What are the booking entries?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:46:55.811Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "zlwndd05kdq4bw4",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "DR financial asset 1 Mio., CR other comprehensive income 1 Mio.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:47:07.117Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "s6hg693a8ny6jqu",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "DR income 1 Mio., CR financial asset 1 Mio.",
      "DR other comprehensive income, 1 Mio., CR financial asset 1 Mio.",
      "DR other comprehensive income 1 Mio. CR financial liability 1 Mio."
    ],
    "question": "Shares are measured at FVTOCI. The value increased from 3 Mio. to 4 Mio. In comparison to last year. What are the booking entries?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:47:31.855Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "...has a range of meanings",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:48:38.824Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "dlbsmasf3uvzmrc",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "...is illegal.",
      "...is considered to always be harmful to shareholders.",
      "...is a valuation technique for intangible assets."
    ],
    "question": "Earnings management...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:48:38.824Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Taking a big bath",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:49:17.736Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "1qpr6uyonvx54pj",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Taking a shower",
      "Jungle Book",
      "Income Balance"
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of an earnings management pattern?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:49:17.736Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "The choice by a manager of accounting policies so as to achieve some specific objective.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:49:57.676Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "f66fnyjlv00ui5y",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Discussions with stockholder",
      "Marketing during slow periods to try and increase sales.",
      "A financial ratio used to better understand the relationship between earnings and sales"
    ],
    "question": "Earnings management is:",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:49:57.676Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Real earnings management takes place during the fiscal year.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:50:35.970Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "dw4ullhgn25ld76",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Choosing a specific write-off period is an example for real earnings management",
      "Accounting earnings management is illegal",
      "Accounting earnings management takes place during the fiscal year."
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true:",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:50:35.970Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Sale-and-lease-back",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:51:17.748Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "nvp593svb5ts11w",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Estimating residual value",
      "Determining a valuation model for property, plant and equipment.",
      "Not to publish the financial statement"
    ],
    "question": "Which of the following can be an example for real earnings management?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:51:17.748Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "...flexibility in accounting standards where choices are specified.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:51:51.543Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "2muatxtxzacgcdp",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "...flexibility in accounting standards where there is no choice.",
      "...flexibility in accounting standards where choices are not specified.",
      "...real earnings management."
    ],
    "question": "The choice between first-in, first-out or weighted average cost (inventories- IAS 2) is an example for...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:51:51.543Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the listed.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:53:19.401Z",
    "footer": "To-Do: rethink multiple choice",
    "id": "j0xv2eg62dtlplf",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Market data",
      "Financial disclosure",
      "Economic data"
    ],
    "question": "Financial statement analysis makes use of:",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:53:19.401Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "...gross profit.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:53:55.852Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "dw5qk8wbczcc34e",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "...net income.",
      "...sales turnover.",
      "...EBITDA."
    ],
    "question": "Deducing cost of goods sold from sales results in...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:53:55.852Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "...cash flow from operating activities and cash flow from investing activities",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:54:28.824Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "wqmylukawfyxlt2",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "...net income and cash flow from financing",
      "...EBITDA and sales",
      "...net cash flow and cash flow from operating activities"
    ],
    "question": "The free cash flow combines ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:54:28.824Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "...the portion of sales that is a profit.",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:55:15.027Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "vb5xd6qmdzfal7x",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "...EBITDA minus depreciation and amortization",
      "...comparison of profit with the investment necessary to generate the profit",
      "...the portion of profit that is sales"
    ],
    "question": "A margin is...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:55:20.640Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Net income / Average shareholders′ equity",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:57:51.983Z",
    "footer": "The slash (/) in the answers stays for a long fraction. I.e. `A/B` means A is divided by B.",
    "id": "gswvodhtvqfno8l",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Net income / Average Net Cash Flow",
      "Total debt / Total shareholders' equity",
      "Total assets / Total shareholders' equity"
    ],
    "question": "Which returns reflects how much profit a company generates with the money shareholder have invested?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:57:51.983Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "...gross margin",
    "created": "2026-02-19 14:58:34.786Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "sbl6ktjwmg60yv0",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "... net profit margin",
      "...gross efficiency",
      "... EBIT"
    ],
    "question": "Dividing the gross profit by sales results in...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 14:58:34.786Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Sales / Total assets",
    "created": "2026-02-19 15:00:18.413Z",
    "footer": "The slash (/) in the answers stays for a long fraction. I.e. `A/B` means A is divided by B.",
    "id": "m4umfilaq0akl2m",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "EBIT / Capital Employed",
      "Total debt / Total assets",
      "Current assets / Current liabilities"
    ],
    "question": "Which ratio reflects the average number of times per period that the money invested in assets is converted into sales?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 15:00:18.413Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Current assets / Current liabilities",
    "created": "2026-02-19 15:01:33.368Z",
    "footer": "The slash (/) in the answers stays for a long fraction. I.e. `A/B` means A is divided by B.",
    "id": "vk1gr76x46pk5ca",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "PPE Investments / PPE Deprication",
      "Total debt / Total assets",
      "Cost of goods sold / Average inventory"
    ],
    "question": "Which Ratio can be used to examine the firm’s liquidity",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 15:01:33.368Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "The financial position on a particular date; i.e. assets, liabilities and shareholders' equity",
    "created": "2026-02-19 15:02:58.153Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "gt95v56h4cvcnzw",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Supplementary information on a firm’s business model",
      "The profit or loss for the accounting period",
      "Compensation plans for the board of directors"
    ],
    "question": "What information can be found in a balance sheet?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 15:02:58.153Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "The firm is growing",
    "created": "2026-02-19 15:04:32.770Z",
    "footer": "The slash (/) in the question stays for a long fraction. I.e. `A/B` means A is divided by B.",
    "id": "t3yzp00mragt9tx",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "The firm is shrinking",
      "The firm is bankrupt",
      "The firm conducts earnings management in an illegal way"
    ],
    "question": "A reinvestment rate above 1 indicates? Recall, the Reinvestment Rate (PPE) = PPE Investments / PPE Depriciation",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 15:04:32.770Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Revenues, expenditures, net profit or loss",
    "created": "2026-02-19 15:05:11.887Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "k3iptyj6zv6xwvd",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Daily stock prices",
      "A reconciliation of the beginning and ending balances of all revenue accounts.",
      "CEO entrance date"
    ],
    "question": "What information can be found in an income statement?",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 15:05:11.887Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Change in share price, dividends",
    "created": "2026-02-19 15:06:04.108Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "vbepto3udeq5zrc",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "EBIDT, EBITDA, and net income",
      "Total assets, net income, dividends",
      "Change in share price, net income"
    ],
    "question": "The Total Shareholder Return includes:",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 15:06:10.144Z"
  },
  {
    "chapter": "k26h3ao2dojgp21",
    "collectionId": "pbc_2001502728",
    "collectionName": "mc_questions",
    "correctAnswer": "Horizontal balance sheet structure",
    "created": "2026-02-19 15:07:21.931Z",
    "footer": "",
    "id": "v9a9qafuast481a",
    "otherAnswers": [
      "Financial profitability",
      "Total shareholder return",
      "Interest coverage"
    ],
    "question": "The Equity-to-Fixed Assets Ratio can be used to examine the firm’s ...",
    "updated": "2026-02-19 15:07:21.931Z"
  }
]